Guide to the Carl and Shelley Smith Mydans Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Subject Files, 1942-2000; Series II; 35.42; (35 boxes)
  - U.S. Military and public information (Box 135)
  - TIME-LIFE Alumni Society (Box 135)
  - Leica Medal of Excellence Award (Box 135)
  - Marcos-Hawaii-New York Times, expenses and story (Box 135)
  - Marcos-Philippines, 1988 (Box 135)
  - Correspondents: Dennis Warner, Bob Shaplen, et al (Box 135)
  - Fortune: stories and suggestions (Box 135)
  - Published TIME and LIFE pictures (Box 135)
  - Angel's Falls, Misty and John (Box 135)
  - "No Greater Love", 1987 (Box 135)
  - Crocker Art Museum: letters from fifth grade school (Box 135)
  - Tom Pepper (Box 135)
  - Photographers and Princess Diana (Box 135)
  - Photographs for collectors (Box 135)
  - Ang Lee, director (Box 135)
  - Captions (Box 135)
  - Tom Bentkowski, Society of Publication Design, 1992 (Box 135)
  - The Violent Peace, 1981 (Box 135)
  - Japan: language (Box 135)
  - AOL/Time Warner merger (Box 135)
  - Xerox of 1978 business expense diary (Box 135)
  - Xerox of 1980 business expense diary (Box 135)
  - Xerox of 1981 business expense diary (Box 135)
  - Xerox of 1982 business expense diary (Box 135)
  - Xerox of 1983 business expense diary (Box 135)
  - TIME, Inc. New York Staff Telephone Directory (Box 135)
  - Rosters (Box 135)
  - Picture department home telephone numbers (Box 135)
  - Rosters, 2 (Box 135)
  - The Violent Peace: complimentary copies sent out (Box 135)
  - Copies of Photojournalism sent to (Box 135)
  - Mailing list-China: A Visual Adventure (Box 135)
  - Mailing and invitation lists (Box 135)
  - Who to send memoir book to (Box 135)
  - TIME, Inc. telephone directory, 1999 (Box 135)
  - TIME, Inc. telephone directory, 1983 (Box 136)
  - The Directory of Members, TIME LIFE Alumni Society, 1998 (Box 136)
  - The Directory of Members, TIME LIFE Alumni Society, 1999 (Box 136)
  - The Directory of Members, TIME LIFE Alumni Society, 2000 (Box 136)
  - The Directory of Members, TIME LIFE Alumni Society, 1996 (Box 136)
  - Editorial Services Address List, 1980 (Box 136)
  - LIFE's 60th Anniversary Issue (Box 136)
  - List of those who received LIFE 60th Anniversary Issue (Box 136)
  - Names: mailing lists (Box 136)
  - Captions and cables: Finland (Box 136)
  - Captions and cables: coverage in and out of Britain, 1952-1954 (Box 136)
  - Captions and cables: Guam, 1945 (Box 136)
  - Captions and cables: Taiwan, 1950 (Box 136)
  - Captions and cables: misc. documents (Box 136)
  - Captions and cables: post-war USA and Canada (Box 136)
  - Captions and cables: Queen in Nigeria (Box 136)
  - Captions and cables: Japan (Box 136)
  - Captions and cables: China, Taiwan, Indochina, 1948-1950 (Box 136)
  - Captions and cables: Korean War, first period, 1950 (Box 136)
  - Captions and cables: Rumania, Yugoslavia, Guatemala, Italy, Samoa, Vietnam (Box 136)
  - Captions and cables: Coverage In and Out of England (Box 136)
  - Reporters notebook, 1947; 2 (Box 137)
  - Names: at photographers gatherings, 1996 (Box 137)
  - Notebook, 1995-1996 (Box 137)
  - Binders: captions and cables, Moscow, 1959-1960; 5 (Box 137)
  - Misc. Moscow correspondence (Box 137)
  - LIFE captions to be assorted (Box 137)
  - Captions and cables: some China duplicates (Box 137)
  - Orangutan and Bali (Box 137)
  - Retrospective: Amon Carter Museum, correspondence (Box 137)
  - Notes on Retrospective, 2 (Box 137)
  - Harry Abrams, Inc., correspondence, agreements with TIME, Inc., contract (Box 137)
  - Harry Abrams: "Carl Mydans, Photojournalist" forward, introduction, captions, 2 (Box 138)
  - Contract: Harry Abrams, "Carl Mydans, Photojournalist" (Box 138)
  - "Carl Mydans, Photojournalist," second printing (Box 138)
  - Harry Abrams (Box 138)
  - Captions for Japan Books: "English captions for my Nikon Japanese book" by Jun Miki (Box 138)
  - Captions for Japan books: Japan occupation years, captions (Box 138)
  - Captions for Japan books: occupation years (Box 138)
  - Captions for Japan books: Japan occupation book (Box 138)
  - Captions for Japan books: misc. (Box 138)
  - Captions for Japan books: U.S. occupation of Japan, 2 (Box 138)
  - Pictures: Philippines set (Box 138)
  - Japan Occupation Book: text, captions, and research, 11 (Box 138)
  - Japan Occupation: xerox copies, 2 (Box 138)
  - Japan Occupation: copies of text and notes (Box 138)
  - Xerox cuts and duplicates from folders 1-5 (Box 138)
  - Japan Occupation: prints weeded out on editing (photocopies), 1995 (Box 138)
  - Japan Occupation: prints, 16 (Box 139)
  - Pictures that might be added to Japan Occupation story "Manly Pine", 1992; 18 8x10 prints with captions (Box 139)
  - "The Manly Pine: American Occupation of Japan", written and rejected, 1981 (Box 139)
  - Trip to Japan: the Japan exhibition and "As We Saw It" (Box 139)
  - "As We Saw It": contracts with Kodansha and PPS, signed and faxed April 7, 1995 (Box 139)
  - Carl Mydans: Japan book and exhibition (Box 139)
  - Carl Mydans: Kodansha contracts (Box 139)
  - Japan book and exhibition: ringed note copies (Box 139)
  - Pacific press: 1995 Tokyo exhibition (Box 139)
  - MacArthur's Japan: introduction and catalogue etc., 1995 (Box 140)
  - Xerox set 2 (Box 140)
  - Pacific press: for Occupation book, Suzanne Goldstein, also bioperse, 1995 (Box 140)
  - "As We Saw It": research notes, random (Box 140)
  - Inserts for Mr. Ishii, 1995; 3 (Box 140)
  - "As We Saw It": drafts and duplicates to be discarded when book is complete (Box 140)
  - "As We Saw It" pp. 1-48, picture numbering revised and page breaks, 1995 (Box 140)
  - "As We Saw It" pp. 1-23 (Box 140)
  - "As We Saw It" pp. 24-38 (Box 140)
  - "As We Saw It" pp. 38-48 (Box 140)
  - Carl's pieces (Box 140)
  - Japan Occupation: introduction, pictures, and videos, 1995 (Box 140)
  - "As We Saw It" misc. (Box 140)
  - Bearse, Ray. "The Compassionate Photographer." Notes and papers on Farm Security Administration and his Mydans chapters, 12 (Box 140)
  - Bikini, 11 (Box 140)
  - Contact sheets of early negatives, 7 (Box 141)
  - Contact sheets, 1979-1982; 4 (Box 141)
  - Black and white conversion prints for "China: A Visual Adventure", 1979; 6 (Box 141)
  - Plains, Georgia and Jimmy Carter, 12 (Box 141)
  - Picture agencies (Box 141)
  - Portraits (Box 141)
  - 35 mm positives for lectures on photojournalism (Box 141)
  - Images (Box 141)
  - Books: Chapter V-Photojournalism (Norman Snyder and Simone Gossner) (Box 141)
  - TIME: 150 Years of Photojournalism, 1989 (Box 141)
  - Howard Chapnick, 1995 (Box 141)
  - Photography: its history (Box 141)
  - Speech before the Ohio News Photographers Convention, 1978 (Box 141)
  - Photography: My Pieces et al., 2 (Box 141)
  - San Francisco Quake (Box 141)
- Personal and Professional Papers, 1962-2000; Series III; 6.5; (8 boxes)
  The series contains notebooks, clippings, awards, and personal effects relating to Mydans' career, dating from 1962 to 2000. Most notably the notebooks provide detailed entries regarding Carl and Shelley Smith Mydans' assignments, including information about subjects and places photographed.
  - Spiral notebooks I: Christians in Japan (Box 142)
  - Spiral notebooks I: Venezuela, 1965 (Box 142)
  - Spiral notebooks I: research: American Samoa, filariasis, 1962 (Box 142)
  - Spiral notebooks I: Delilah (Box 142)
  - Spiral notebooks I: Venezuela, second visit, 1966 (Box 142)
  - Spiral notebooks I: US customs (Box 142)
  - Spiral notebooks I: Bulgaria/Romania (Box 142)
  - Spiral notebooks I: Moscow/Billy Graham, 1984 (Box 142)
  - Spiral notebooks I: Moscow, 1992 (Box 142)
  - Spiral notebooks I: Angel Falls and Mt. Auyantepui (Box 142)
  - Spiral notebooks I: Captions: Overland Train, 1963 (Box 142)
  - Spiral notebooks I: Tahiti, Samoa, 1962 (Box 142)
  - Spiral notebooks I: Rio de Janeiro [and] Tristan de Cunha, 1963 (Box 142)
  - Spiral notebooks I: Romania (Box 142)
  - Spiral notebooks II: Virgin Islands, 1967 (Box 142)
  - Spiral notebooks II: Fortune-Japan, 1969 (Box 142)
  - Spiral notebooks II: Overseas Chinese, 1970 (Box 142)
  - Spiral notebooks II: Polar Siege, Alaska, 1964 (Box 142)
  - Spiral notebooks II: Photograph: year-end issue, 1966 (Box 142)
  - Spiral notebooks II: Vietnam (Box 142)
  - Spiral notebooks II: Sri Lanka, 1975 (Box 143)
  - Spiral notebooks II: Russian Boarding School, Moscow (Box 143)
  - Spiral notebooks II: Japanese self-image (Box 143)
  - Spiral notebooks II: Fortune piece--notes (Box 143)
  - Spiral notebooks II: Costa Rica, 1964 (Box 143)
  - Spiral notebooks II: Thailand and Philippines (Box 143)
  - Spiral notebooks II: Israel (Box 143)
  - Spiral notebooks II: Indonesia trip (Box 143)
  - Spiral notebooks II: Elizalde story, 1970 (Box 143)
  - Spiral notebooks II: Summing up (Box 143)
  - Spiral notebooks II: Vietnam 1-5 (Box 143)
  - Spiral notebooks II: Vietnam 6-7 (Box 143)
  - Spiral notebooks II: Easter Island Bio 1-3 (Box 143)
  - Spiral notebooks II: Easter Island 1-4 (Box 143)
  - Spiral notebooks II: Easter Island 5-8 (Box 143)
  - Spiral notebooks II: Easter Island 9-11 (Box 143)
  - Spiral notebooks II: Easter Island 12-13 (Box 143)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): The Bikinians: A Study in Forced Migration (Box 143)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): Bali, 1973 (Box 143)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): Singapore, Chinatown (Box 143)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): Bikini (Box 143)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): Carter coverage (Box 143)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): Langkawi--Shelley (Box 143)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): Democratic Convention, 1976 (Box 143)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): "Moonlight"--Jim Thompson, 1974 (Box 143)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): Turtles (Box 143)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): Notes--day Claire was born (Box 143)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): Ceylon/Kenya, 1975 (Box 143)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): Ceylon and Royal Botanic Gardens (Box 144)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): Turtles (Box 144)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): Tamen Nagara National Park, Malaysia (Box 144)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): The Oil Palm (Box 144)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): India (Box 144)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): Singapore-Bangkok train (Box 144)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): Langkawi (Box 144)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): China, Shanghai (Box 144)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): Burma (Box 144)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): Rotan (Box 144)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): Burma Dancers (Box 144)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): Bali, 1973 (Box 144)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): Singapore (Box 144)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): Chinatown (Box 144)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): Orangutans, Sepilock, 1973 (Box 144)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): Mersing, Rawa, Pemangil and Tioman Islands, Malaysia, 1973 (Box 144)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): Shelley's notes on travel in Egypt, Israel, London, 1975 (Box 144)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): TIME stories: Diego Garcia, Asian Businesses, Ocean Park Hong Kong, 1977 (Box 144)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): Sir Fitzroy Maclean, A.B. Guthrie, Jr., 1964 (Box 144)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): War book interviews, 1965 (Box 144)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): Return to Bikini I, II, and IV (Box 144)
  - Spiral notebooks III (Singapore years): Return to Bikini V and captions (Box 144)
  - Spiral notebooks and calendars, 2000 May (Box 144)
  - Spiral notebooks and calendars:, 2000 June (Box 144)
  - Spiral notebooks and calendars: Carl, I-VI (Box 144)
  - Spiral notebooks and calendars: planners, 1991-2000; 11 (Box 145)
  - Spiral notebooks and calendars: notebook, 3 (Box 145)
  - Articles about Mydans (Box 145)
  - TIME: 150 Years of Photojournalism (Box 145)
  - LIFE: 60th Anniversary issue (Box 145)
  - The Digital Journalist, 1999 (Box 145)
  - LIFE Celebrates 1945 (Box 145)
  - Publications by and about photojournalists, 13 (Box 145)
  - Camera technical booklets, 12 (Box 145)
  - Photo albums and scrapbooks, 4 (Box 145)
  - "The Rock": Eddie Adams Workshop gift of appreciation, 1990 (Box 146)
  - International Center of Photography Lifetime Achievement Award, 1992 (Box 146)
  - Kodak Lifetime Achievement Award, 1988; 4 (Box 147)
  - Awards, 4 (Box 148)
  - TIME, Inc. Lifetime Achievement Award, 1997; 4 (Box 149)
  - Platinum Pocket Warmer, 4 (Box 149)
  - Gloves, 4 (Box 149)
  - Leather camera case (Box 150)
  - Example of one of Mydans' boxes (Box 150)
- Writings and Other Papers, 1956-2005; Series IV; 19.84; (16 boxes)
  The series contains research notes, drafts of writings, proofs, printed material, contracts, and correspondence relating to Carl and Shelley Smith Mydans' writing projects dating from 1956 to 2005. Material documenting Shelley Mydans' creative process and books The Open City, Thomas: A Novel of The Life, Passion, and Miracles of Becket, and The Vermilion Bridge can be found in this series. The series also includes material produced during the Mydans' collaborations, most notably The Violent Peace as well as various books about Carl Mydans' photography.
  - The Open City
    - "Open City"--Reviews, 3 (Box 151)
    - "Open City", 3 (Box 151)
    - "Open City": Shelley's first draft (Box 151)
  - Thomas: A Novel of the Life, Passion, and Miracles of Becket
    - Notebook: "Materials for the History of Thomas Becket", 8 (Box 151)
    - Thomas: typescript (1-4 of 5 folders), 4 (Box 151)
    - Thomas: typescript (5 of 5 folders) (Box 152)
    - Thomas: notes and criticism (Box 152)
    - Passion and Miracles, 3 (Box 152)
    - Research for "Thomas", 2 (Box 152)
    - "Thomas": notebooks, 8 (Box 152)
    - "Thomas" Chapter X (Box 152)
    - "Thomas": first draft, 7 (Box 153)
    - Passion and Miracles: outline and summary (Box 153)
    - "Thomas": notes and criticism (Box 153)
  - Vermilion Bridge: outlines, summaries, book jackets, 10 (Box 153)
  - Reference materials (photocopies), 6 (Box 154)
  - Pamphlets and cards, 2 (Box 154)
  - Pictures from "Pacific Friend" (Box 154)
  - Pictures from the Horyu-ji (Box 154)
  - Catalogues, 2 (Box 154)
  - Family trees (Box 154)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 154)
  - Notebooks: Japan and Buddhism, 12 (Box 154)
  - The Floating Bridge: Chapters 1-6, 1975 (Box 154)
  - The Floating Bridge: Chapters 1-15, 1976 (Box 154)
  - The Floating Bridge: Chapters 1-23, 1978 (Box 155)
  - Production material, 4 (Box 155)
  - Early drafts of Vermilion Bridge, 2 (Box 155)
  - Early drafts of Vermilion Bridge, 4 (Box 156)
  - Notebooks: Buddhism, 3 (Box 156)
  - The Vermilion Bridge: press release (Box 156)
  - Changes in chapters (Box 156)
  - The Vermilion Bridge: original typescript (1-2 of 3 folders), 2 (Box 156)
  - The Vermilion Bridge: original typescript (3 of 3 folders) (Box 157)
  - The Floating Bridge: typescript, 2 (Box 157)
  - A Floating Bridge: early materials, 3 (Box 157)
  - The Vermilion Bridge: research, box containing index cards (Box 157)
  - Cuba, 2 (Box 157)
  - Colombia: La Violencia in Colombia (Box 158)
  - Venezuela: Terror in Venezuela (Box 158)
  - The Dominican Republic: The Dominican Upheaval (Box 158)
  - Congo: research and manuscript (Box 158)
  - Simba Rebellion, 2 (Box 158)
  - Angola: eyewitness and research, 1961 (Box 158)
  - India-China: border conflict (Box 158)
  - The Violent Peace (Box 158)
  - Indonesia (Box 158)
  - India-Pakistan: The Flare-Up in Kashmir, 1956 (Box 158)
  - The Philippines, 2 (Box 158)
  - Laos: The Beleaguered Neutral (Box 158)
  - Vietnam: eyewitnesses and research (Box 159)
  - Arab-Israeli War, 3 (Box 159)
  - "What is Peace?" (Box 159)
  - The Battle for Mungo Hill (Box 159)
  - Burma (Box 159)
  - The Violent Peace: printer's manuscript, 5 (Box 159)
  - The Violent Peace: working copy (3 of 5 folders), 3 (Box 159)
  - The Violent Peace: working copy (2 of 5 folders), 2 (Box 160)
  - The Violent Peace, 5 (Box 160)
  - War (Box 160)
  - Atheneum (Box 160)
  - The Violent Peace: correspondence, reviews, and outlines, 7 (Box 160)
  - Prisoners of War, 2 (Box 160)
  - Public information (Army, Navy, etc.) (Box 160)
  - War (Box 160)
  - Terrorism (Box 160)
  - Weapons (especially newfangled Vietnam failures) (Box 160)
  - Terrorism-guerrillas-mass killing-Mao's guerrilla teachings (Box 160)
  - Armed forces (Box 160)
  - Armament, disarmament, and tools of war (Box 160)
  - United Nations (Box 160)
  - Violence/crime (Box 160)
  - Bridges (Box 160)
  - Cold War (Box 160)
  - Colonialism, independence (Box 161)
  - Coups d'etats (Box 161)
  - Genocide, man's brutality to man, mass killings, etc. (Box 161)
  - Chemical and bacterial warfare (Box 161)
  - Defection (Box 161)
  - Foreign Legion (Box 161)
  - Hijacking-the 20th century (Box 161)
  - Limited war (Box 161)
  - Lists of wars since 1945 (Box 161)
  - Medicine and wounded in war (Box 161)
  - Mercenaries (Box 161)
  - Nationalism and territory (Box 161)
  - My Lai (Box 161)
  - NATO (Box 161)
  - Building the US Army (Box 161)
  - Sanctions and embargos (Box 161)
  - "Pueblo" (Box 161)
  - Slavery (Box 161)
  - The Violent Peace: chapters and corrections, 5 (Box 161)
  - China Civil War (Box 161)
  - Indochina: Fight for a Lost Empire (Box 161)
  - Greece (Box 161)
  - India-Pakistan: Partition of India (Box 161)
  - Arab-Israeli struggle for peace (Box 161)
  - Malaya (Box 161)
  - War book manuscript: Police Action in Korea 1950-1953, copied drafts (Box 161)
  - Quemoy-Matsu (Box 162)
  - Algeria 1952-1962: eyewitness reports and research (Box 162)
  - Brother vs. Brother in Algeria (Box 162)
  - Hungary, 1956 (Box 162)
  - The Suez Crisis (Box 162)
  - The Sinai Campaign (Box 162)
  - Yemen and South Arabia (Box 162)
  - Cyprus (Box 162)
  - Shurkin, Joel. "Terman's Kids" (Box 162)
  - "Thomas" correspondence, 1965-1969 (Box 162)
  - Shelley: talks and projects, 2 (Box 162)
  - Wagner, Lilya. Book on women correspondents (Box 162)
  - Sorel, Nancy Caldwell. Women war correspondents, 1991 (Box 162)
  - Shared housing (Box 162)
  - Nimitz Museum (Helen McDonald), 1993 (Box 162)
  - Habitat for Humanity: international and information (Box 162)
  - The Vermilion Bridge: reviews (Box 162)
  - The Vermilion Bridge: letters, 1981 (Box 162)
  - The Vermilion Bridge: since publication (Box 162)
  - Verses from Manyoshu and elsewhere for chapter heads and quotes (Box 162)
  - Japanese edition (translators, correspondence) (Box 162)
  - The Vermilion Bridge, 1982 (Box 163)
  - "Enemy National" contract, 1988 (Box 163)
  - Correspondence with Wm. Collins, Inc., 1966 (Box 163)
  - "Open City" correspondence and records (Box 163)
  - "Passion and Miracles" correspondence (Box 163)
  - Thomas: Doubleday, William Morris correspondence, 1965-1975 (Box 163)
  - "Thomas" as a play (by Philip Hanson) and correspondence with Owen Laster (Box 163)
  - "Thomas" reviews, 2 (Box 163)
  - Shelley's talks, 1977-1978 (Box 163)
  - Shelley: royalties, 1982 (Box 163)
  - Correspondence with Doubleday (Box 163)
  - "Treasures from the Horyu-Ji" for ASIA, 1981 (Box 163)
  - El Camino Real and California Missions (Box 163)
  - Seminar on Buddhism, 1980; 2 (Box 163)
  - The Charlie Rose Show, 1992 (Box 163)
  - Manila: notes on elections and notebooks, 1986 (Box 163)
  - Northern California Presbyterian Homes (Box 163)
  - Women at War: Eddie Adams Workshop (Box 163)
  - Shelley's pieces (Box 163)
  - Correspondence with the Pacific Press Service regarding publication, 1995 (Box 164)
  - Book of photographs, largely in Japanese, with photographs by Carl Mydans and text by Shelley Mydans, published by the Pacific Press Service, 1995 (Box 164)
  - Japan Essay, 1949, contacts, 3 (Box 164)
  - Material regarding Pacific Press Service publication, including list of assignments for LIFE, correspondence, and biographies, 1995-2005 (Box 164)
  - List of Mydans' photographs exhibited at Life Gallery of Photography, 1995 (Box 164)
  - Contact sheets of photographs taken in Japan from 1945 to 1977, undated; 6 (Box 164)
  - Contract with Pacific Press Service regarding traveling exhibition, and photocopies of photographs, 1995 (Box 164)
  - Correspondence with Pacific Press Service regarding publication As We Saw It, photocopies of Life articles, photocopy from exhibition catalogue on Tadahiko Hayashi (Tokyo Metropolitan Museum of Photography) (Box 164)
  - Shimbun, Journal of the Foreign Correspondents' Club of Japan, containing articles about Mydans, 1995 (Box 164)
  - Biographical information for catalogue, material regarding Hayashi Exhibition and Edo-Tokyo Museum, photocopies of photographs, 1994-1995 (Box 164)
  - Japan Essay, 1949, contacts, 2 (Box 165)
  - The Manly Pine: Japan Under U.S. Occupation, text by Shelley Mydans to accompany photographs by Carl Mydans (Box 165)
  - Tadahiko Hayashi X Carl Mydans: Japan as seen by Japanese and American Photojournalists, exhibition catalogue, Pacific Press Service, 1995 (Box 165)
  - Carl Mydans: A Photojournalist's Journey Through War and Peace, exhibition catalogue, Amon Carter Museum, 1986 (Box 165)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1977-1999; Series V; 1.33; (1 box)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  The series contains audio recordings, including interviews, dating from 1977 to 1999. Interviewees include Alfred Eisenstaedt, Kelly Johnson, Aziza Mowlem, and Oscar Lubow.
  - Eisie, 1977; (1 audiocassette) (Box 166)
  - Kelley Johnson: Skunk Works, 1977; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 166)
  - Oscar Lubow on photojournalism and magazines, 1978; (1 audiocassette) (Box 166)
  - Interview with George Silk, 1982; (1 audiocassette) (Box 166)
  - Aziza Mowlem, 1999; (1 audiocassette) (Box 166)
- Oversize and Other Storage, undated; 2.08; (11 boxes)
  - The Violent Peace, 2 (Box 167 (Oversize))
  - Yali, 2 (Box 167 (Oversize))
  - RA/FSA book-in-the-making, 2 (Box 167 (Oversize))
  - "Thomas" scrapbooks (1-3 of 4), 3 (Box 168 (Oversize))
  - "Thomas" scrapbooks (4 of 4), 3 (Box 169)
  - Awards, 3 (Box 170 (Oversize))
  - Misc., 3 (Box 170 (Oversize))
  - Chungking Color, 1941, 3 (Box 170 (Oversize))
  - Stone prints of the Bikini story, 3 (Box 170 (Oversize))
  - Color and black & white personalities/portraits, 3 (Box 171 (Oversize))
  - Mounted photographs, 2 (Box 172 (Oversize))
  - Mounted photograph, 2 (Box 173 (Oversize))
  - "Stone" prints, 10 (Box 174 (Oversize))
  - Photographic prints, 10 (Box 175 (Oversize))
  - Photographic print, 10 (Box 176 (Oversize))
  - Smithsonian color separations of Burma Dance, 12 (Box 177 (Oversize))
  - Posters (Box 178 (Roll))
- November and December 2015 Acquisitions, 1935-2015; 31.06; (36 boxes)
  Organized into three series: Numbered notebooks, 1935-2000; Other notebooks and personal Papers, 1939-2015; and Slides, 1968.
  - Numbered notebooks, 1935-2000
    - Notebook 1 - Texas; Louisiana; Hollywood; FL; FSA; Hired by Life 11/15/36, 1935-07-12-1939-07-19 (Box 179)
    - Notebook 2 - Ezra Pound; France; NY; Washington, D.C. Wright Field; Finland; Stockholm, 1939-07-20-1940-08-19 (Box 179)
    - Notebook 3 - War coverage in Asia; cables, 1940-08-20-1941-07-25 (Box 179)
    - Notebook 4 - Shelley's notebook; NY; First trip to China, Stockholm, Lisbon, London, Nantucket; Chinese family Lung Chuan I, 1940-01-28-1941-10-26 (Box 179)
    - Notebook 5 - Santo Tomas (notes 7/25/41-1/18/42 burned in Bayview hotel; notes 1/18/42-2/28/43 given to Swiss consulate and put on Teia Maru), 1942-01-18-1943-02-28 (Box 179)